If you visit a bank, this video is
for you. Today I'll talk about five
scams that you can fall prey to.
If you visit a bank,
usually when we visit a bank,
bank officials often try to offer us different plans.
Here, we often have to take plans to oblige us.
So today we'll talk about how you
can withdraw from an account. Before we start the video,
I'd like to introduce myself.
My name is Raleen Kaur, and
I'm a certified financial planner.
Every week I bring you videos to make
your personal financial life easy and
happy. Because our company's
tagline is also "Creating a Belt of
Happiness." Let's move on to the video, which is
called Five Traps to Avoid When You Go to
Bank. So, first of all, when you
visit a bank and you're about to make your deposit,
what happens there? You
tell the bank manager or the bank of fashion that you want to
withdraw. They'll say it's a very good
guaranteed product, you'll take it. So, be
careful here.  The question is, for what
purpose are you doing HD? If you are doing HD
because you need liquidity, then
if you just enter the product, then it is the
traditional plan of insurance, it is the
endowment plan, the return you will get there will be
five to six days later,
defending on your future because there is a
mobility charge also and that is a long
term commitment plan, it is a 10 year, 15
year, 20 year plan. If
you have come to invest in FB here, then it is short term money which
you will withdraw in three years or five years,
perhaps, but the bank will tell you that this
money which you invest in liquid or life insurance will be
tax free, instead
you are putting in FB is taxable,
so keep in mind that in this track, if
you want a life and short term policy, then first of all,
take Tom and Jones, to protect your life and
your family,
only from this region, these production
tax returns are long term
returns, look at your goal,
what is your financial goal, if your
financial goal is that you want to do this for a short period
and  If you want your money back after some time, then
definitely HD will suit you.
These financial products will not suit you.
Before falling into this trap, you should check whether
that policy fulfils your needs or
not. It is important to check this. So,
understand that if you are being told that there is
another guaranteed plan where there are
higher returns, then understand why the HD of the bank is
giving less returns, why are those products
giving higher returns, then do a complete
research and only then
invest in it. Many times it happens that we
register with the intention of investing in HD
but we take the insurance policy and go home
and then what happens is that we keep having multiple
policies and we do
not even open their renewal page because that
reminder does not come and we do
not know how to manage those policies,
what are its returns,
what are the benefits of that policy, we went to register for HD and
simply sent a Facebook message, it came back. It is
very common that when you register for HD, some boy or
girl will be sitting there and they will tell you,
Sir Madam, your number has been selected, you have been
our bank account holder for a long time.  If yes, then they are
offering you a free of cost credit card, please don't fall into this trap.
If you
want a credit card, then give it to us. It's a
different thought. If you don't want it, then do
n't take a credit card just because
you are special and you have been selected and
you are getting it free of cost. It's not like that,
everyone will say that. So keep this thing in mind. Keep that
credit card in track.
If you don't want it, then don't take another
credit card. Don't add another credit card to your card.
Buying unnecessary third party mutual funds
from the bank without risk-reward ratio. Understand what is a big thing.
We enter the bank
and think that our money is
100% safe. Whether we are investing in the bank or in
mutual funds, it is still safe.
You should also understand that mutual funds are
private asset management companies
and they work with a certain amount of money
in everything. But with a certain amount of money,
you should know the risk and return ratio very
well.
You should be investing in this product.
Many times the thought process is commenting, then that will be the same, it is
not like that, you should complete your due diligence,
if you want to take that risk then only
invest in mutual funds and I
Bill suggests that you invest in one place, you will
keep your consolidation at one place,
you know, one is from neutral funding, one is from
neutral funding bank, one is through mutual
fund distributor, one is
through online portal and so on so butter you cup, you should
understand your mutual fund place and risk reward only after which mutual fund should you
invest in, many times you will be
approached by many people saying that this
new fund has come, it is a very good fund, you will get this much
return guaranteed, there is
no such thing as guaranteed
in mutual funds, you should understand because as they say
mutual funds, in these sir subject market rise,
please offer document, be careful before
and vesting, so your duty is divided that you will
not read the document but you should
understand what is the risk
Before investing in your mutual fund, do
not invest blindly. Forth, buy
group health insurance from the bank. This is the
next trap. What is happening now is that many
people are approaching you to
buy insurance through the bank, which you
get expensive outside, but cheap in Mac. Hey brother,
look at the correct language, why are you getting insurance because it is in
group insurance. The
features of group insurance are different.
Group insurance product itself is a different
type, this is not in retail. In short, and policy
means if you are buying a policy from an insurance company
versus buying it from a bank
and it is getting cheaper than the one bought from the bank, then it is
important to know why it is getting cheaper.
You people are very smart, you do complete research on
things. If something is available cheaper, then
you ask why it is getting cheaper.
Here, it is important to know why it is getting cheaper. There is
some reason for it being cheap because it is a group
insurance product, hence it is getting cheaper. The
bank negotiates the
terms and conditions and pricing with the insurance company,
also forget the customer. So when they negotiate,
of course, when the pricing  We
will negotiate that we will give you a big chunk of business
to the insurance company, so you make us a group
policy which is only for our policy
holders, then the terms and conditions
will also be negotiated, secondly, if tomorrow
you want to port this policy then it is
not possible on group insurance policy,
so I am telling you from experience that a lot of people are falling into this
trap, they are
taking the policy through banks, they are
abandoning their original policy which was in place for so many years,
secondly they will never
ask you about your medical conditions,
before onwarding you, you will
not get a proposal form, everything will be done after negotiating, then
ultimately you will face problem at the
time of claim because there it is between
you and the enjoyment company,
what is your India,
contractor with the insurance company, so it is between both of you,
please start, when you are going through the bank, then keep in
mind that for after sales
service, you will have to
contact the insurance company only, I
am not a dedicated agent, can  Take care of
this so make sure you buy retail health and
soren so only group help do
not enter into these institutions just because the spring is low
then the premium is low and so are the benefits fifth
last but note de list when you go to the bank to open a locker then they
tell you
that you will have to make a fixed deposit
so the fixed deposit which you will have to make is
equal to three years of
rent plus locker breaking charge if your
rent for the locker is ₹6000 or ₹8000 then
accordingly these three plus a little breaking
charge will be levied this is the rule of RBI they
cannot tell you that you will have to make an HD of ₹50000 only then
you can open a locker in the bank
you can refuse because you are
aware you know that these are the rules
so it is unnecessary now HD due to this reason
because you have to open the locker and you are
intelligent you will not get it done do
your due diligence you are aware you should do your due
diligence  Take any step only after this,
so this does not apply to the bank,
it applies to every company, whenever you are going to
buy these financial products, then it is
necessary for you to do your due diligence. We
say that misselling happens in the exchange industry or
investment industry.
What is misselling, that the wrong
product is sent by the advisor, distributor,
but it is misdirected from the bill. You are an
investor, you are informed, you are a policy
holder, you are informed. When you yourself are
entering into something, then understand
what I am entering into, what is the service, what is the risk,
understand the conditions very well, then enter the supply of
financial products, so if you have any
questions, you
want to share your feedback because many
people share their feedback with me that
this happened in a bank, this happened
more than before, so if you also have
some such feedback, please share it
in the comment section and before going, quick
reminder, if you have not yet subscribed to our channel, then
subscribe so
date  You can do right information and you can do right
time see you soon with the next video
Steve take care by